Let's look at this image of a mountain.
我们来看这张山峰图
This is Mt. Rainier in Washington state.
这是美国华盛顿州的雷尼尔山
Most features on this and any other image fall into one
这图里的大多数特征 或者说任意图像的大多数特征
of three categories: edges, corners, and blobs.
都逃不出三大类 边缘、角点和斑点
Edges we're already very familiar with,
边缘我们已经很熟悉了
they're are just areas in an image where the intensity abruptly changes.
就是图像强度发生突变的区域
Also known as areas that have a high intensity gradient.
也称为高强度梯度区域
Corners are at the intersection of
角点则是两个边缘相交的地方
two edges and form what looks like a corner or a sharp point.
看起来像是个角或一个尖锐的点
And the blobs are region based features that may include areas of
斑点则是按特征划分的区域 可能是强度特别高或特别低的区域
extreme highs or lows in intensity or areas of a unique texture.
或是具备独特纹理的区域
We'll be most interested in detecting corners because they're
我们最想检测的就是角点
the most repeatable feature which means that they're
因为角点是可重复性最高的特征 也就是说
easy to recognize given two or more images of the same scene.
给出关于同一景象的两张或以上图像 我们就能很轻易地识别出这类特征
As a simple example let's look at this image of
来看一个简单的例子
a Mondrian painting and let's look at these three patches: patch A,
我们来看这张蒙德里安的画作 来看这三小块
B, and C. Given these three patches
A、B 和 C 有了这三小块
can you tell me what rectangular area they match with on this image?
你能告诉我它们位于图像的哪个矩形区域吗？
Patch A is just a single patch of color and it
A 只是个简单的色块
matches with a lot of areas like this all around the rectangle.
能和许多这样的矩形区域匹配
So this is a bad feature because it isn't unique.
由于它不是独一无二的 所以不是个好特征
Patch B is an edge we know because of
B 是边缘
its orientation that it matches with an edge at the bottom of the red rectangle.
因为从 B 的方向来看 B 与红色矩形底部的边缘相匹配
But we can still move this edge to the left and right and it would still be a match.
但我们还是可以左右移动这个边缘 B 左右都能匹配
We can only approximate where this edge appears on this image.
我们只能估测这个边缘在图像上的大概位置
It's very hard to get the exact location.
但很难找出确切位置
Patch C is a corner.
C 则是个角点
It actually contains two corners and
实际上 C 包含了两个角点
its location is easily identified as the bottom right.
其位置也很容易确定 就在右下角
This is because a corner represents a point where two edges change.
这是因为角点代表两个边缘变化的交点
And if we move either of those up or down
如果我们将其上下移动
the corner patch will not match exactly with that area.
这个角点块是无法准确地匹配这部分区域的
So corners are easiest to match and make good features because they are so unique.
所以角点是最容易匹配的 是独一无二的 因此是好特征
Next let's see a more complex example of where corners are useful for
接下来 我们来看一个更复杂的例子 这个例子很好地体现了角点的实用性
identifying points on an object and get some practice coding a corner detector.
因为它能识别物体上的点 然后我们还要做些练习 编写角点检测器的代码. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6